Robley Gori

An energetic, competent software developer with years of verifiable experience working with technologies and languages including and not limited to Python, Java, Node.js, and DevOps to deliver user-centred solutions on the web and mobile applications.

EXPERIENCE

Angaza, Kenya — *Python Developer*

DECEMBER 2022 - PRESENT

I built and maintained integrations with mobile networks in multiple markets to facilitate payment collections and communication between small merchants and their clients.

I worked with project managers, developers, quality assurance and customers to resolve technical issues to enable a smooth flow of payments.

Leveraged technologies: Python, Flask, PostgreSQL, React.js, and AWS.

Laws.Africa, South Africa — Senior Python Developer

AUGUST 2019 - NOVEMBER 2022

I contributed to the <u>Indigo platform</u> that aims to improve access to African law through the most extensive free and open access repository of African gazettes by implementing new interface designs, adding new backend functionality and integrating new technologies. Indigo is used in several countries across Africa to publish legislation online including Kenya, Namibia, South Africa and Zimbabwe.

I built a caselaw management system for the National Council for Law Reporting in Kenya enabling them to process and publish thousands of court cases weekly as part of their mandate.

Leveraged technologies: Python, Django Framework, PostgreSQL, and Elasticsearch.

Safaricom PLC, Kenya — Java Developer & DevOps Associate

MARCH 2018 - JULY 2019

I spearheaded the efforts that contributed to the design & implementation of microservices architecture geared toward achieving a mobile-first dream through mobile apps. This includes the Safaricom Home App that helped 100,000 users(Google PlayStore downloads), manage their home internet subscriptions and subscribe to new offerings.

Leveraged technologies: Java, Spring Framework, Docker, Kubernetes, Grafana, JMeter, Apache Kafka, and Jenkins.

Phone:

+254 722 161224

Email:

robleygori@live.com

Website:

robley.dev / Github

SKILLS

(Languages, Frameworks, & Technologies)

Fluent

Python Javascript

Proficient

Vue.js HTML/CSS Docker Elasticsearch SQL Git AWS Dokku

Familiar

Rust React JS Java Kubernetes Redis

Interests

Systems programming Data Science Blockchain AI

Andela, Kenya — Software Developer

JUNE 2017 - JULY 2019

At Andela, I worked on the open-source data management system CKAN by building out new features in the form of extensions. I also worked on internal tools as part of the technology team.

Leveraged technologies: Python, Pylons Framework, React.js, Node.js, and PostgreSQL.

PROJECTS

DoomAlerts

A bot I built to notify me in advance of planned power interruptions by Kenya Power.

Tech used: Rust, Docker, Dokku, AWS.

Fleetz

Is A Twitter bot that lets you post self-destructing tweets.

Tech used: Python/Django, PostgreSQL, Docker, Dokku, AWS.

Toa Sauti

Is A platform designed to enable the public to give valuable information to the authorities in an effort to boost public contribution to curbing crime.

Tech used: Python/Django, MySQL.

Midget

A fast, minimalistic URL-shortening platform built on Django, Vue.js, and Redis as the primary data store.

Tech used: Python/Django, Vue.js + Vuex, Redis, Bootstrap.

EDUCATION

Multimedia University of Kenya, Kenya

Bachelor of Science, Information Technology --- JULY 2017

Programming Coursework: Data Structures and Algorithms, Database Systems, Object-Oriented Programming, Operating Systems & Distributed Systems.

CERTIFICATIONS

Scrum Fundamentals Certified